你们听过江湖这地方吗？
Have you ever heard of Jiang Hu?
别想从地图里找
Don't bother Iooking it up in the atIas
你们一定找不到
You won't find it there
江湖是一个不讲法律的地方
Jiang Hu is a pIace without Iaw
那儿只有规矩道义和恩怨
There are onIy ruIes, honor and rivaIries
其实不 同的人有不 同的江湖
Different peopIe have different Jiang Hu
如果进过我这个江湖的话
If you happen to be in my Jiang Hu
你就一定听过任因久
You must know of Jim Yam
这个响当当的名
He's very famous
没有？
Never?
那你见识太少了
Then you don't know anything
我就是任因久
I'm Jim Yam
江湖人，白羊座
I'm from the underworId. Aries
我负责的社团叫洪宝
I'm in charge of the group Hung Bo
现在我很忙
I'm pretty busy now
在忙什么？
Busy with what?
我正在谈判
I'm negotiating
任老久，现在世界变了
Master Yam, the worId has changed
你那套不管用了
Your oId ways don't work anymore
你实在太落后了
You're out of date
看看你…
Look at you ...
知不知道现在的年青人在想什么？
You know what young peopIe
think about now?
你懂不懂什么叫上网？
You know what the internet is?
什么叫？lPO？
You know what IPO is?
你知不知道什么叫lPO？
搞网页资讯公司呀
It means setting up IT companies
一个星期筹备
... that can be Iisted on the stock market
六个星期上创业版那种
in Iess than 6 weeks
这叫做时代步伐
That is the modern way
江山代代有人出
There's aIways a new generation
你已上岸，就退下来吧
You've made it, now make way for us!
我说完了，不再说了
I'm done, I'm finished
你也无话可说吧
And you haven't said anything?
为什么？
Why?
因为我有论点
Because I have a point
大口连，一九九七年六月二十六日
Big Mouth, on 26th June, 1997 ...
在福临门你借了我三十万
... you borrowed $3OO,OOO from me
你有没有还过我一个仙？
But have you ever paid me back?
你竟用这种语气跟我说话？
How dare you taIk to me
with this attitude?
那晚你点了两只吉品鲍
That evening, you ordered two
expensive abaIones
开了一瓶八二年Lafite
... and opened a bottIe of Lafite of 1982
结单连小费总共一万两千五
The biII to that meaI was $12,5OO
我还没跟你计较
and I haven't asked you to pay the biII
要谈判？
You want to negotiate?
你连本带利还清这笔账才有得谈
We'II taIk when you've paid back
your debt, with interest
就这样
That's aII
这件事你没跟我说过
You didn't teII me about this
这时候别跟我说这种话吧
Don't say such things to me now
我知道，我对大口连砸瓶那件事
I know the news of me hitting
Big Mouth with a bottIe ...
不用一晚，就会传遍整个江湖
... wiII spread in the underworId tonight
其实当大哥，有时真要出来做场好戏
But a Triad boss must put on a show
from time to time
目的就是要跟着你的那班手下知道
... to Iet your men know that ...
你还很猛，很活跃
... you're stiII powerfuI
我习惯夜生活，皮肤缺乏健康色素
I'm used to night-Iife, and I Iook paIe
所以我很喜欢晒太阳灯
so I Iove to sunbathe in tanning booths
来保持我的健康肤色
... to keep a heaIthy Iooking tan
他叫阿愉，我的贴身保镖
He's Yue, my bodyguard
亦是我最能打的手下
... and the most IethaI of my men
阿愉以前是甲组球队队员
Yue used to be a Division 1
soccer pIayer
曾夺两届香港足球先生荣誉
& was awarded twice Mr. soccer of HK
他踢球时受伤累累
He had a Iot of injuries pIaying soccer
全身镶上了许多钢片
And he has steeI parts impIanted
in his body
所以每次上飞机检查时都会响警钟
At the airport, he aIways sounds
the aIarm at the inspection point
不过，也有一点好处
There's an advantage to that
挡子弹时会硬实点
He can shieId me from buIIets
more efficientIy
久哥，这么高兴
Brother Jim, what a night!
看来要庆贺一下
I think we shouId ceIebrate
高兴是应该庆贺的
Yeah, we shouId ceIebrate
去JoJo那边吧
Let's go to Jo Jo's pIace
师爷伟最了解我
ConseIor Wai understands me the best
他跟我以前，在律师事务所当师爷
He worked in a Iaw firm
before working for me
我认识他
I met him when my first wife
是因为我跟第一任太太离婚
and I were getting divorced
他居然代表我太太来跟我谈判
He represented my wife against me
结果被我打得鼻肿脸青
... so I beat him up badIy
他很喜欢混黑社会
He Ioves Iife in the underworId
自己已是黑社会
Even though he's a triad member
还买每期古惑仔来看
he stiII reads scoundreIs, the comics
你说怪不怪？
Isn't that strange?
差不多了
That's about it
阿伟，你可以回去了
Wai, you may go home now
是，久哥
Yes, Brother Jim
阿叶，你也收工吧
Yip, you go home too
阿愉，你等我
Yue, you wait for me
是，知道了，久哥
Yes, got it, Boss
JoJo是我的情妇
Jo Jo is my mistress
我是在很偶然机会下认识她
I met her in a taiIor shop
任先生，请问你平常习惯放左边
Mr. Yam, which side do you prefer
还是右边？
Ieft or right?
你真坏
You're naughty!
我左不放右不放，就放你里面
Neither Ieft nor right
I prefer it inside you
任因久！
Jim Yam!
你恶贯满盈，我要替天行道
You're eviI, I must act for God
铐你回去！
I must arrest you!
好！你放马过来！
sure, come on!
你以为这样就可捉到我吗？
You think you can catch me?
不要…
No ...
救命呀！   敢铐我？
HeIp! How dare you?
不铐了…
I dare not ...
我弟弟最近加入黑社会
My younger brother has joined
the triad recentIy
还跟了你手下
... and your man is his boss
你给他机会吧
Look after him
阿愉
Yue
你去跟烂口昌说
Go and teII Rod Cheung
他手下停车的咸蛋超有个小子
that Chiu, the vaIet boy has taken a kid
糟了…
Damn ...
叫什么？
What is he caIIed?
反正不是阿威就是阿武
It must be either Wai or Wu, anyway
是不是有人搞他？
Is someone picking on him?
不，他是JoJo的弟弟
No, he's JoJo's younger brother
叫他有位就让他上吧
Promote him when there's an opening
是，知道了，久哥
Yes, got it, Boss
我跟你说过多少次
How many times have I toId you?
是即知道，知道即是
Yes equaIs to got it
车里只有我和你，不用叫久哥了
You needn't caII me Boss
when we're aIone
是，知道了，久哥
Yes, got it, Boss
我有情妇，因为我有个老婆
I have a mistress because I have a wife
我有老婆，所以我才有情妇
I have a wife, therefore I have a mistress
这道理，所有男人都明白
And aII men understand that Iogic
女人在我生命中
In my Iife, women ...
绝对不会占百份之十以上
... don't have an important pIace
而这百份之十
And this minor position ...
当然不止由一个女人分享
... must be shared by different women
她是我老婆苏花
she's my wife, sophie
目前正经历人生一个重要阶段
she's at the most criticaI period
of her Iife
直接影响到我的健康
... which directIy affects my heaIth
有人叫这阶段做虎狼之年
PeopIe refer this as the Hungry
Tigress period
老公，你是不是不行？
Hubby, have you become impotent?
两夫妻的事不怕说嘛
We're a coupIe, you can teII me
我知道你不喜欢
I know you don't Iike that
但我托朋友给你买了两盒威而钢
But I asked my friend to buy you
some Viagra
来帮你
They can heIp you
什么不行？
What do you mean?
我就做给你看
I'II show you my power
有些东西，就算多好玩
However much fun a game is ...
做得太多也会觉得辛苦
... you'II tire of it if you pIay it too much
你别看我老婆骚成这样
My wife Iooks fIirtatious now ...
老公…
Hubby ...
在其他人眼中，她却是另一个人
she shows another side in front of
other peopIe
你们别当大哥是傻瓜
Don't treat your Boss Iike a fooI ...
想怎样就怎样
... and do whatever you want
阿南，你档子亏了本与大哥何干？
Nam, your faiIing business has nothing
to do with the Boss
前几年还说，开档时算大哥一份
When you started your business
you promised that he wouId be a partner
这两年赚到钱了
But when you made money
也不见你分一仙过来
you never gave him a penny
现在亏了本，就开口向大哥要钱
Now you're Iosing money
you want his heIp?
大嫂…
sister ...
戴超！
Thai Chiu!
你伙同外面堂口的人开片
You started a war with a rivaI gang ...
事前有没有通知大哥？
... did you aIert your Boss beforehand?
没有吧
Right?
现在死了人才向大哥大报销
Now you come to cIaim from Boss
when someone is dead
那小子我见都没见过
WeII, I have never seen that guy
还是巴基斯坦人
... and he's a Pakistani
你们人人来找大哥便宜
You keep taking advantage of the Boss
他好人，不吭声
He's kind, he never bIames you
回来不高兴，就拿我这女人出气
But when he comes home
he takes it out on me
他明知吃亏，也不责怪你们
He never bIames you even though
you cheat him
讲义气嘛
That's honor!
谁最惨？
Who reaIIy suffers?
还不是我这个女人？
Me, I'm the reaI sufferer!
一句话，是不是要我承受？
Just one word, you aII want me
to suffer?
大嫂，不是这样的
sister, it's not Iike that!
不是这样就行了
Then it's simpIe
摊开笔账，公公道道算一次
We'II go through the Iedger
and settIe it now
阿愉，下去看看什么事
Yue, go and check it out
什么事？
What is it?
What is going on?
阿叶，窗子打开一点
Yip, open the window a bit
我是见习督察叶伟信
I'm WiIson Yip, Inspector Trainee
见习是吧？
Trainee?
有件事，我有义务告诉你
There's something I have to teII you
说
shoot
有话大声说吧
say it IoudIy
二十四小时内有人要杀你！
someone wiII kiII you in the next
24 hours!
你疯啦？
Are you crazy?
他叫我大声说的
But he asked me to say it IoudIy
任因久，我跟你说过了
Jim Yam, I have toId you
没什么，想跟你说件事
Nothing, I onIy want to teII you
something
自从我任因久出来混
Ever since I have been
in the underworId
每天都有人想杀我
... peopIe try to kiII me everyday
但二十多年来，我还活着
But I have survived through
the Iast 2O years
伟，看那个见习在哪上班
Wai, check where that trainee works
明天叫人送个水果篮过去
and send a fruit basket to him tomorrow
消息准确吗？
Is the news reIiabIe?
愉，看到那枪手吗？
Yue, you see that sniper?
街口数过来第一幢，白色那座
The first white buiIding
第一个天台右边角落
... from the first right corner on the roof
愉！
Yue!
这枪不响？
This gun doesn't work?
抢枪我还没说你
You snatched my gun without asking
过去一点，很挤
Move over a bit, it's tight
那枪手也不是很准的
That sniper isn't very accurate
不，久哥，很准呀
No, Boss, he's accurate
我中了枪
I got shot
但我顶得住
but I can take it
久哥，现在怎办？
Brother Jim, what shaII we do now?
通知四大公司开会
AIert the 4 organizations for a meeting
我要知道谁跟我过不去
I want to find out who did that
用什么名义？共商善举？
What's the excuse? Charity?
有没有更响亮点？大家想想
Anything grander? Let's think
要不就叱责…
How about ...
急成这样，江湖告急吧！
How about Jiang Hu Gao Ji?
是，知道了，久哥
Yes, got it, Boss
这个名字不错
It's a good name
看来没事，又好像有事
It sounds Iike nothing
but couId be something
有事呀警察，报警吧
something is going on, caII the poIice
打电话回你公司叫人吧
CaII your peopIe for heIp
久哥，早
Morning, Brother Yam
早，阿伟
Morning, Wai
行不行？
Is it okay?
漂亮吗？
Looks good?
很好呀
Very good
Versace，当然好
It's Versace, of course it's good
Versace？没见过
Versace? Haven't seen this before
是防弹衣，你当然没见过
It's buIIet-proof
you wouIdn't have seen it before
他们有生产防弹衣？
Do they make buIIet-proof jackets?
那防弹衣真是奇丑无比
That oId buIIet-proof jacket was ugIy
我特意买件大码Versace回来改给久哥
so I bought a L-sized Versace
to convert it
原来出自嫂子的手笔
sister, you designed it
难怪这么有灵气
No wonder it's so eIegant
如果你大量生产
If you mass-produced it ...
江湖老大人人身穿一件，那就发啦
... and aII the Triad bosses wore one
you wouId be rich
苏花连蛋都没下过一只
sophie has never produced one baby ...
你跟她说大量生产？
... and you want her to mass-produce?
你好坏，一大早就挖苦人
You're terribIe, picking on me so earIy
久哥，这么早找我什么事？
Brother Jim, what can I do for you?
没什么，我想问问你的看法
Nothing, I want to get your opinion
现在有人用枪暗杀我
There's an assassin after me
我已派所有兄弟出去打听了
I've sent aII my men out to find out
who's behind it
江湖事，我想还是江湖解决吧
I suggest to resoIve it the triad way
我们找到主谋又怎样？
What if we find the person behind it?
把他剁成九块？
shaII we chop him to pieces?
我没好处吧
It doesn't do me any good
都传开了，怎能没有动作？
Everyone knows about this
so we must take action
所谓有危就有机
Opportunity comes in dangerous times
我们应该利用这个机会
We shouId make use of this opportunity
你想到办法？
You have a pIan?
还没有，快了
Not yet, but very soon
不如
What if ...
不如就…
利用这个机会，排除异己
we use this as an excuse to get rid of
our rivaIs?
对
Right
应该利用江湖告急这个会议
We make use of ''Jiang Hu Gao Ji''
meeting
看清楚四大公司的立场
to see where the 4 organizations stand
看看到时谁说话大声过我
Whoever speaks Iouder than me
at the meeting
我就说他是主谋
... I'II say he's the conspirator
完全同意
I compIeteIy agree
任老久，你放心吧
Jim Yam, don't worry
只要知道是哪班人干的
Once we know who the pIotter is
我们所有堂口的人都不放过他
... none of our members wiII spare him
现在就是不知哪班人暗算他
We don't even know who wants
to kiII him
是想杀他呢
Whether he wants to have him kiIIed ...
还是只想警告他，我们都不知道
... or just to warn him
任老久，我们出来闯的
Jim Yam, we're in the underworId
近来开罪了谁，怎会不知道呢？
You shouId know if you have offended
someone recentIy
反正你现在还没死
since you're stiII aIive ...
他们随时会再出击
they may make another attempt at you
到时你来一招引蛇出洞
You can set up traps for them
知道了谁干的，便叫齐人马摆平他
and when you know who did it
get rid of him
我是最多心的
I'm aIways suspicious
久哥会不会怀疑
Does Brother Jim suspect
是我们当中的人干的？
one of us did it?
我老表华发誓，一定没干过
I swear I didn't do it
基哥，你一晚没吭声
Brother Kei, you haven't said anyhing?
平常你很多话的
You usuaIIy have Iots of opinions
是呀基哥，你今晚好安静呀
Right, Brother Kei, you're siIent tonight
没什么，我也遇上了头号杀手
Nothing, I've aIso ran into an kiIIer
我今早看过报告
I read the report this morning
医生也证实了，说我有肺癌
The Doctor has diagnosed me
with Iung cancer
争？争什么呢？
so why wouId I compete with you?
多年来，我们都在争地盘
We've been fighting each other
for territories aII these years ...
你劈我，我砍你
... in endIess vioIence
到头来，我连自己的地盘都没搞好
In the end? I can't even maintain
my own territory
我们今天不是讨论争地盘
We're not discussing territories today
我认识一位气功大师，我介绍给你
I know a qigong master
I'II introduce you to him
有了，有种果汁，能医百病
Yes, there's a kind of fruit juice
that heaIs aII diseases
我找人搬几箱给你试试
I'II send a few boxes for you to try
基哥，你放心
Brother Kei, don't worry
以后用得着我老表华，尽管出声
Just teII me if ever you need me
总之我任因久今天在此跟大家说
Let me teII everyone present
如果给我发现是谁跟我过不去
If I find out who stands against me
我一定不放过他！
I wiII not Iet him Iive!
基哥，还有样东西你可以试试
Brother Kei, there's one thing
you can try too
西藏雪莲
Tibet snow BIossom
这宝物有病治病，没病强身
It heaIs aII diseases indeed
贵不贵呀？
Is it expensive?
买不到的
It's not for saIe
小子，跟着我干什么？
Hey, why are you foIIowing us?
我来找久哥
I came to see Brother Jim
久哥，我想跟你
Brother Jim, I want to work for you
什么？你是谁？
What? Who are you?
我本来跟大口连的
I used to work under Big Mouth
但上次见你砸他的头
but after I saw you hit him with a bottIe
我觉得他不够份量
I think he's not quaIified
所以我想转堂口
That's why I want to switch
叫什么名？
What's your name?
罗金虎，叫我阿虎行了
Law Kum Fu, just caII me Tiger
你刚出来混的？
You're new to the underworId?
没人教你忠义两个字怎样写？
No one ever taught you about LoyaIty?
跟大哥和玩女人有什么分别？
What's the difference between
foIIowing a boss and pIaying a woman?
女人你不满意，可以叫她滚
If you're not happy with a woman
you can cast her out
她滚慢点还可以飞脚踢她尾龙骨
If she refuses, you can even kick her
可以这样对大哥吗？
But can you do this to your boss?
不懂回答可以问我手下
Ask my men if you don't know
the answer
我只知道，现在世界已经变了
I onIy know the worId has aIready
changed
你一定想过，如果我不收你你会怎样
You must have considered what
wouId happen if I rejected you
我会建议你小心提防
I wouId advise you to be carefuI
因为你一定会后悔
... as you'II definiteIy regret it
说什么？小子！
What do you mean?
不是对你说
I'm not taIking to you
我任因久从没做过后悔的事
I've never done anything that
makes me regret
除了一次
... except once
你不用问我，跟你不太熟我不会说
Don't ask, I won't teII you
as I don't know you
十三妹！
sister 13!
很久没来打通宵牌了
You haven't come for aII-night mahjong
in a Iong time
最近有没有玩切手指？
You stiII pIay the game of cutting
fingers?
有，这个月十七八根吧
Yes, I've cut 18 fingers this month
妹姐，是十九根
sister, 19 in totaI
对，忘了你多手呢
Right, I forget you're an octopus
碰！
Pong!
指指划划干什么？
What are you pointing at?
原来没有
Oh, there's nothing
没有就闪开，不然切了你那根
step aside if you have nothing
or I'II cut yours off
摸吧
Get one
你这混蛋又来了
This asshoIe is fIipping out again!
叫糊了
Last one for me
这家伙不对劲，先叫救护车
There's something wrong with him
send for an ambuIance
是谁？
Who is he?
冰冰旗下的东东
It's Tung Tung, he works for Ping
你没听过他唱歌吗？
You havent' heard him sing?
阿冰，怎么你旗下歌手…
Ping, you mean the singer
under your IabeI ...
…也能唱歌？
... can reaIIy sing?
不，打五万块底的麻将才这样的
No, he's Iike this when he pIays
high stakes mahjong
糊牌的话，更可怕呢
He's worse when he wings a hand
可别糊呀，我好的
Don't win, I'm scared
叫糊啦！
Last one for me!
快点吧
Hurry up!
糊牌！
Made it!
这么大，糊死你啦
It's a big game
他真的有事呀，叫救护车
There's reaIIy something wrong with
him, send for an ambuIance
不…他常常这样的
No ... he's aIways Iike this
久哥，今天我和东东来…
Brother Jim, the reason I come here
其实不是来打牌的
... is not to pIay mahjong
我们有件事…想请你帮帮忙
In fact, we ... want to ask you a favour
到底什么事？
What is it?
这件事很长篇很凶险的…
It's a very Iong and dangerous story ...
让我说！
Let me teII it!
他最近被狗仔队跟踪
The paparazzi has been after him
有次进男厕，他见到有个记者
One day he went to a toiIet
he saw a reporter
拿着什么针孔镜头，偷拍他撒尿
fiIming him pissing with a micro camera
但我手快，拿东西泼他
I was fast enough to spray him
所以他没拍到我
He didn't get anything of me
狗仔队也是听老板吩咐办事
The paparazzi just take orders
from their boss
是的，那老板有问题呀
Right, the probIems came from the boss
知道是哪家？
You know which paper?
查到了
I've checked it aIready
那老板是男是女？
Is the boss a man or a woman?
男的，有分别吗？
A man, what's the difference?
江湖规矩，男的揍一顿
underworId ruIes, for it's a man
we beat him up
女人呢？
What if it's a woman?
用屎泼她
We spIash her with shit
我想知道，如果不男不女又怎样？
What if he's sort of a transvestite?
揍一顿再用屎泼
Beat him up then spIash him with shit
还有什么问题？
Anyhing eIse?
没有了
No
其实我们当大哥的
Being a boss Iike me ...
真的不能随便乱说话
... shouIdn't say things casuaIIy
我可以举以前一件事做例子
Let me give you an exampIe
要不要我下来把着你的手教你怎做？
Must I hoId your hand and teach you
what to do?
发生这种事当然出江湖奸杀令啦
For such a case, of course
we'II send men to rape then kiII
我只说一次！
I won't repeat it!
什么？
What?
你好像说了江湖奸杀令
You seem to have said ''a rape then kiII''
什么奸杀令？
What ''a rape then kiII''?
那反骨仔是男的，当然出江湖追杀令
That traitor is a guy, of course
是女的才出奸杀令嘛
We onIy rape and then kiII
if it's a femaIe
但你的确说了江湖奸杀令嘛
But you did say ''a rape then kiII''
阿愉，我说了什么？
Yue, what did I actuaIIy say?
刚才阿伟说的好像是
You may have said what Wai cIaimed
不过久哥你说不是，又好像不是
since you say you didn't
maybe you didn't
就是嘛
That's right
不如补多个电话给阿发作实吧
You'd better give Fat a caII to confirm it
这么说，我说错话了？
You mean I made a mistake?
你刚才没听到，我只说一次嘛
Didn't you hear me say I won't repeat it?
你要说，你来打
You want to teII him, you caII
你打给阿发吧，来
Give Fat a caII then, come on
你真的说了奸杀令嘛，久哥
Brother Jim, you reaIIy said
''a rape then kiII''
阿发，你听错了吧
Fat must have misheard it
就算是也不用这么严重吧
Maybe it was a mistake, this is overkiII
很痛的
That hurts
久哥
Brother Jim
亏佬基刚刚在医院死了
Kei just died in the hospitaI
是吗？
Did he?
帮我拿件外套，我们走吧
Get my jacket, Iet's go
要这么快去医院，久哥？
Brother Jim, we're rushing to
the hospitaI?
我几时说去医院？
Did I say we were going to the hospitaI
去喝奶茶呀
We're going to have a cup of tea
去哪里喝奶茶？
亏佬基的地头有家奶茶档很出名
There's a good tea-house where
Kei used to be
我们平常不去，趁这机会去嘛
We couIdn't go in the past
now we can go
快点，走吧
Hurry, Iet's go
虎哥，我们近来很不济呀
Brother Tiger, times are tough
these days
过来基哥这边，一点油水也没捞到
We haven't made any money working
for Brother Kei
是呀
That's right
我们现在连代客停车也捞不上了
We can't even make money
in vaIet parking
阿细昨天抢劫被警案抓走了
sai was arresed of robbing a shop
yesterday
我们连五千块保释金也拿不出
We couIdn't even coIIect $5,OOO
for his baiI
阿B说想去卖迷幻药
Bee wants to seII ecstasy
但我们也要有本钱呀
But we Iack the capitaI
就这么多，拿去吧
This is aII I have
我再想办法
... I'II think of something
这里除了奶茶，蛋挞也很好
Besides tea, egg tart is aIso good here
以前只能叫外卖
We couId onIy caII for deIivery
in the past
今天来吃新鲜
Now we can have them fresh here
先给点吧
Pay and I'II owe you
没有
No money
若大一个人上街，一百几十也没有？
You don't have $1OO? Come on
我全部家当都在这了
AII my beIongings are here
哪够呀？
It's not enough
伙记
Waiter
所有钱都在这，不够等会再还你
AII the money is here
I'II get you more Iater
大哥，不是吧？这样不行的
Boss, come on, that won't do
你是怎样当大哥的？
What kind of boss are you?
整班手下都在你面前装死狗
Every time your guys pretend to be poor
你就把所有的全给他们
You give them aII the money you have
我朋友说，他们每晚泡女
My friends say they go chase girIs
every night
不知多豪爽
... and they are big spenders
只有你才这样呆头呆脑
OnIy you're stupid enough
to beIieve them
人家叫你一声大哥，就晕头转向了
You get high just having them
caII you boss
打吧！
Beat me now!
做你女朋友早就准备挨打了
I expect to be beaten
being your girIfriend
我现在打电话，拿电话来
I want to make a caII now
bring me the phone
没电呀！
No more battery!
伙记
Waiter
是
Yes
那张桌的单算我的
Put that tabIe's biII in on my biII
给我奶茶    好
A tea pIease Yes
不用说了，我不会让你跟我
No need to say it
I won't Iet you work for me
这钱算我先欠你
Then I owe you
一百几十，算了
It's nothing, forget it
做人要算清楚
It's better to keep it cIear
看什么？
What are you Iooking at?
我认得你，踢足球的
I recognize you, you used to be
a soccer pIayer
神经病！
Nuts!
我见到这个不知好歹的小女孩
When I saw that feisty IittIe girI
就马上想起我老婆
... I thought of my wife
她以前，是另外一个人
she used to be a totaIIy different person
那时我走投无路，潜到英国
some peopIe were after me
I fIed to EngIand
别动！打劫！
Don't move! HoId-up!
不想脊背开两个洞就别动
Don't move if you don't want hoIes
in your back
Carl！
CarI!
苏花，打劫时别叫我的名字呀！
sophie, don't say my name
when we're puIIing a job!
你也叫呀
But you said mine too
搜他的身！
search him!
拿去用吧
Take the money, OK
什么？
What?
不用怕，我不打女人的
Don't be afraid, I never beat women
最多用屎泼你
The most I'II do is to spIash women
with shit
不过现在没有
But I don't have any right now
你想怎样？
What do you want?
赔我一个饭盒
Buy me a Iunch box as compensation
饭盒？
Lunch box?
我只得一个饭盒
That was the onIy Iunch box I had ...
现在被你打翻了，怎么办？
... and you dropped it
那我请你吃饭吧
I'II treat you then
请我吃饭？
Treat me to a meaI?
吃完饭，你就有东西消化
You'II have something to digest
after you eat
有东西消化，你就有屎泼我了
... then you wiII have shit to spIash me
苏花她真的请我吃饭
sophie reaIIy invited me to Iunch
而且还吃得很痛快
and I enjoyed it very much
简直可以用宾至如归来形容
I can onIy describe it as ''weIcoming''
起初我想食宿靠她
At first I wanted to Iive on her
又因为很久没碰过女人
And because I hadn't touched a woman
for a Iong time ...
不如随便一点无所谓吧
... I thought I might be casuaI with her
没想到后来…真是随便了
But soon it ... reaIIy became casuaI
苏花
sophie
你有什么人生理想？
Do you have any dreams?
我的人生理想…
My dream is ...
可不可再来一次？
... that we do it one more time?
别动
Don't move
是个日本仔
It's a Jap
混蛋！去！
Bastard! Go!
进去！
Go inside!
那时候，我们生活还算无忧无虑
We had no worries then
不是吃就是睡
We ate and we sIept
没钱吗？就去抢
We needed money? We robbed
快点
Hurry up
男的面向墙！
Guys face the waII!
女的把东西全拿出来！
GirIs take everything out!
这档子的东西挺多的
That's an interesting staII
对了，大家同声同气
Right, we're feIIow countrymen
是中国人吧？
You're Chinese?
算你便宜点，随便看…
I'II give you a good price, take a Iook ...
这块玉挺有趣
This piece of jade is interesting
不过心形太老套了
The heart shape is a bit oId-fashioned
什么老套呀，大姐？
What do you mean oId fashioned?
你有所不知了
Let me teII you
你听过什么叫人心玉造吗？
Have you heard of Heart of jade?
人心肉做我就听过
I've heard of Heart of man
两码事！
They're not the same!
玉造的意思即是矜贵
Jade products are rare and precious
包你大富大贵呀
I guarantee you'II be rich
if you owned one
这话中听！
I Iike this pitch!
你喜欢？
You Iike it?
信不信由你
BeIieve it or not
早前唐人街大哥戴了块一模一样的
The triad boss of Chinatown wears one
Iike this
一到荷兰，叱咤风云
and he's become a tycoon once
he went to HoIIand
发了大财
He made big money
所以你们出来混的，不戴块玉不行
You underworId peopIe must have
some jade ornaments
你怎知道我是出来混的？
How do you know I'm in the
underworId?
到了我这把年纪，一眼就看出来了
At my age, I can teII by a gIance
大哥
Boss
臭婆娘！抢东西！
Bitch! Robbers?
我以为一辈子都要留在伦敦做贼
I thought we'd stay in London
and rob forever
没想到天无绝人之路
but the heavens heIped me
终于可以回香港了
I can finaIIy return to HK
怎么？仇家给干掉了？
Why? Your rivaIs are dead?
我连续买了十期六合彩
I bought 2O consecutive draws
on the Iottery
这次要是让我中了金多宝
and I've won the first prize ...
这世界有了钱就可解决困难
With money, we can soIve aII probIems
我要回去重整旗鼓
... I must go back and start over
我要建立自己的堂口，然后…
I must buiId up my own organization
and then ...
任因久，我不会让你离开我
Jim Yam, I won't Iet you Ieave me
知不知道我最讨厌什么？
You know what I hate most?
什么？
What?
就是被人用刀架着脖子
I hate others putting a knife on my neck
你叫苏花，这就是你的主题曲
You're caIIed sophie
so this is your song
任因久！
Jim Yam!
玩过了就溜！
You Ieave after screwing me?
我诅咒你被香港仇家剁成二十九块！
I hope you wiII be chopped up
by your rivaIs in HK!
十块喂狗，十块填海！
and they cut your body into pieces!
最后九块削片！削成一片片！
I wish they sIice your muscIe
into thin pieces!
你这千刀万剐的东西，快去死吧！
You damned bastard
why don't you go to heII?
用不着这么毒吧
Do you have to be so wicked?
你不是回香港吗？
Haven't you gone back to HK?
哪敢回去呀？
How do I dare?
不怕给人剁成二十九块吗？
I'm afraid my rivaIs wiII sIice me
into thin pieces
不要紧的
I don't care
换成我，也会回去
I'd return to HK if I were you
我去买了个箱子
I bought a suitcase
让你收拾东西跟我回香港呀
... for you to pack your things in
and come back with me
这么难看！
It Iooks awfuI!
好低档的箱子，哪里买的？
Where did you get such a cheap
suitcase?
好难看呀！你什么品味呀？
You have no taste at aII!
拿回去换吧！
Go back and exchange it!
你一定没拿收据吧
You didn't get a receipt
不要紧，我们去抢一个
It's okay, Iets go and steaI another one
快点吧！好难看呀！
Hurry! That Iooks awfuI!
多难看，怎么提上街？
I can't carry it outside
我就喜欢这箱子！
I Iove this suitcase!
不喜欢就不回香港了！
If you don't want it, don't come back
to HK with me!
不是呀
Hey
这行李箱也很独特的
This suitcase is quite unique
很漂亮呀
It's pretty
你的品味真是顶呱呱
You reaIIy have good taste
我们在行李输送带那边
When we wait in front of the
Iuggage beIt
一定很容易看到我们的箱子
... we can find our Iuggage easier
一定认得出来
We'II recognize it
在街上很抢眼的
And it's eye-catching
回去收拾！
Go home and pack
从此苏花就跟了我
Then sophie married me
她脚头相当不错
she brought me a Iot of Iuck
跟我多久我就发多久
I've been doing weII ever
since we married
不过，她也曾因我而出事
And she suffered for me too
那一次，我真的很难忘记
I'II never forget that time
任因久
Jim Yam
如果你不交批货出来
If you don't hand the stuff over ...
别怪我对嫂子不客气
I won't be kind to your wife
你别以为抓了我老婆就可威胁我
Don't think you can threaten me
with my wife
她跟了我，就预料会有今天
she knows the risks of being
married to me
不过我要警告你
But I must warn you
她若少条毛，你就大件事了
You'II die horribIy if she even Ioses one
strand of hair
你别这样吓唬我吧
Don't threaten me Iike that
我捉她的时候，不好意思
When I was kidnapping her ...
她的确掉了不少毛
... she Iost a Iot of hair aIready
现在事情闹得够大了
This has become a big deaI
但不知道，是你大件事还是我大件事？
... but I'm sure it's a bigger deaI for you
刚才你也听到你老公多不听话
You just heard how your husband
taIked to me
他说，我大件事呀
He said I was in big troubIe
不过我不知道
But I don't know ...
是我大件事，还是你大件事？
... if I'm in bigger troubIe or you are
求我吧
Beg me
你真是丢尽黑社会的脸！
You're a disgrace to the triads!
用这么低劣的内裤来堵我嘴？
You use such a cheap underpants
on me?
低劣？不低劣
Cheap? Not at aII
你这么高档，我特意脱我那条堵你呢
You're a Iady so I took off my own
for you
如果你是低档，我就用我手下的
If you were cheap, I use my men's
underwear
专家来了
The professionaI has arrived
专家？
ProfessionaI?
专家
ProfessionaI
给我把她的衣服一件一件脱下来
Take off her cIothes one by one, now
拍清拍楚！
Keep the photos cIear!
然后将相片寄给她老公！
& then send the photos to her husband
没问题
No probIem
久哥
Brother Jim
有封信
You have maiI
是不是大嫂的？
Is it sister?
他们脱光她的衣服，拍下一辑相片
They stripped her naked and
took photos of her
牛屎强，你叫人脱下我老婆衣服
Ox Dung, you had my wife cIothes
taken off
拍辑相片给我是什么意思？
... and sent me the photos
what does it mean?
脱下衣服，就是告诉你
I took her cIothes off cos I wanted to
teII you ...
你老婆没穿衣服呀！
that your wife was as naked as a frog
你要威胁我，拍套衣服干什么？
Why take photos of her cIothes
to threaten me?
只拍衣服？
Photos of her cIothes?
没…没拍人吗？
Didn't they photograph her?
不是说那摄影师很专业吗？
Didn't you say it was a professionaI
photographer?
他们禁锢大嫂的地方不出三个
They have onIy 3 pIaces to hoId her
一是牛屎强自己的架步
First, whorehouses owned by Ox Dung
一是别人的架步
second, whorehouses owned
by his buddies
再不就是牛屎强和别人合份开的架步
Third, whorehouses owned
by Ox Dung and his buddies
久哥，人手调度没问题
Brother Jim, our men are ready
不过这次行动，预算花多少？
What is the budget for this operation?
如果大嫂在这里，她会说省点用
If sister were here, she'd prefer
to spend Iess
而我主张应花就花
But I say we shouId spend accordingIy
最要紧做得妥妥当当！
It's important to do it properIy!
老婆，你怎么回来的？
Honey, how come you're back?
你别过来！
Don't come near!
这秘密我不会告诉你，永远不会！
I wiII never teII you, this is my secret
never!
我没追问过我老婆
I never asked her about it
以下你们见到的…
What you are about to see ...
只不过是我的幻想
... is my fantasy onIy
你要答应我
You must promise me ...
绝不可放过牛屎强这禽兽！
... that you wiII never spare Ox Dung!
牛屎强最后的下场是很悲惨的
Ox Dung ended up horribIy
我要每个得罪我的人都付出代价！
Those who offended me must pay!
不然，我根本不能在江湖上立足
Otherwise, I couIdn't Iast Iong
in the underworId
任老久，这么迟？
Jim Yam, why so Iate?
我收风不够你们快嘛
I don't receive news as fast as you do
哪里
Not at aII
听说有人…
I've heard someone ...
急匆匆前往亏佬基的茶餐厅喝茶
... rushed to have tea at Kei's tea-house
在那边开完会，顺道喝杯茶而已
I had a meeting near there
so I had a drink afterwards
这要向大家申请吗？
Do I have to get approvaI first?
阿基刚刚过身
Kei has just died ...
你们大家不要吵好不好？
... and so pIease stop quarreIIing, OK?
大嫂，节哀顺变吧
sister, pIease accept my condoIences
基哥纵横江湖几十年，总算不枉此生
Brother Kei sureIy had a briIIiant Iife
有什么用得着阿久的，你尽管说
Just teII me if you need my heIp
阿基去了，各位有心了
Thank you aII for caring
最怕你越帮越忙吧
I just fear your heIp wiII turn into troubIe
是呀，大嫂
Right, sister
我们都是兄弟，你放心吧
Thank you aII for caring
阿基走了，我真不知该怎么好
Now that Kei is dead
I reaIIy don't know what to do
之前他没有任何先兆，说走就走
He died aII of a sudden, so abruptIy ...
连一句话也没交代
... that he didn't Ieave any message
儿子读电脑，什么也不懂
My son knows nothing
except computing
突然这样，你们教我该怎样？
TeII me what I shouId do now
妈，别太伤心
Mom, don't be so sad
大嫂，生意上的事
sister, regarding Kei's business
最要紧交给信得过的人
I suggest you hand it to someone
reIiabIe
千万不要信错人呀
... be carefuI who you trust
人刚刚才去，说什么公事？
Don't taIk business
not before the funeraI is over
我们先想想怎样搞治丧委员会吧
We'd better set up a funeraI committee
基嫂，你回去好好休息
sister, you'd better take a rest
这里我们开会解决，你放心吧
We'II hoId a meeting and
resoIve everything, don't worry
谢谢各位
Thank you again
不要客气
You're weIcome
派人送大嫂回家
send sister home
有什么事情，也要先办了白事再说
We must finish the funeraI before
proceeding to anything eIse
人家还有班手下看着我们
His men are watching us cIoseIy now
利益的事我们迟些才谈
... Ieave the business!
久哥，这么凑巧？
Brother Jim, what a surprise?
没什么，认识你十几年都没来过你家
I've never seen your pIace
in the ten years I've known you
所以买包橙上来看你
so I got some oranges and here I am
谢谢
Thanks
抽雪茄？
You smoke cigar?
朋友留下的
My friend Ieft them here
地方挺好的
Very nice pIace
小地方，容易打理嘛
WeII, smaII fIat is easy to cIean up
摆的？
It's for show?
我以为你只爱看漫画
I thought you onIy read comics
每样都看看，久哥
I try to read a bit of everything
我倒杯茶给你
Let me get you some tea
难怪每次打扑克都不见了小丑
No wonder the CIown cards
are aIways missing
原来都被你拿走
... as you have taken them aII home
喝茶，久哥
Have some tea, Brother Jim
谢谢
Thanks
随便坐
Have a seat
又是小丑？你很喜欢小丑吧
CIown again? You Iike cIowns a Iot?
这幅是毕加索画的
This is a picture by Picasso
两年前在苏富比那儿投来的
I bought it at an auction
毕加索，好东西
Picasso, good stuff
参观一下你的房子
May I Iook around?
随便
PIease
吓我一跳！
This is quite a shock!
我以为平时跟我的是另一个阿伟呢
This makes me think that the Wai
who works for me is someone eIse
久哥，好不容易来一趟
Brother Jim, you've come aII the way
here ...
一定有正经事吧
... you must have something to say
没有
WeII ...
亏佬基死了
Now that Kei is dead
现在只剩下陆老四和彭焦跟我玩
OnIy Luk see and Pang Chiu are
my rivaIs
我想评估一下自己的实力
I want to assess my own power
我很清楚任因久的个性
I know Jim Yam very weII
从第一颗子弹射向他开始
Every since the first buIIet shot at him
他已经想看清楚身边每一个人
he's wanted to Iook cIearIy at everyone
beside him
在香港
In Hong Kong ...
为黑社会办事
a Iot of peopIe who are not Triad
members
但又不是黑社会的人很多
work for the Triads
我只不过是其中一个
I'm onIy one of those peopIe
在我心目中
In my mind ...
跟着任因久不过是份工作
... working for Jim Yam is mereIy a job
for me
其实跟哪个大哥都一样
It doesn't matter which boss I work for
当然，我不会让他知道
I won't Iet him know this of course
忠肝义胆
Honor and IoyaIty ...
今时今日，都是演技搭够吧
but nowadays everyone puts on an act
right?
愉，怎样？
Yue, how is it?
久哥，你先走，我还顶得住
Brother Jim, you Ieave first
I can hoId on
傻啦？风大雨大怎么走？
Nuts, it's dangerous, how can I Ieave?
久哥，我现在出去跟他拼了
Brother Jim, I'II go and fight him
一有机会，你立刻走！
Run when you can!
要拼就一起拼
Let's fight together
不行，你不可以有事
No, I can't Iet anything happen to you
出来混的都预着了
It's part of the Iife
久哥，其实有些人
Brother Jim, some peopIe
注定要为其他人而死
are destined to die for others
阿愉
Yue
有件事，我想说了很久
There's one thing I have aIways
wanted to teII you
其实我一直…
In fact, I have aIways ...
一直…
... aIways ...
都爱你
... Ioved you
这时候你还说这样的话？
How can you say such a thing now?
我知道你一时间很难接受
I know it'II take time for you to accept it
但我不说，恐怕没机会了
but I'm afraid I won't have another
chance to teII you
阿愉！
Yue!
告诉我，谁叫你来杀我？
TeII me, who sent you to kiII me?
你是？
You are?
关云长！
Kwan Wan Cheung!
什么？
What?
关云长！
Kwan Wan Cheung!
请喝茶，先生
Have some tea, sir
有劳嫂子
Thank you, sister
不用客气
You're weIcome
嫂子，请坐
sister, pIease sit down
我有…我有事办
I have ... something to do
看球赛吧
Watch the match
今晚车路士对纽卡素
CheIsea vs NewcastIe
球赛？
A match?
是呀，坐…
Yes, sit down ...
给我多派两个人去医院看着阿愉
send more men to the hospitaI
to protect Yue
通知他们上我家开会
TeII them to come for a meeting
at my pIace
再派人封死来我家的路
AIso bIock the road to my pIace
为什么用英泥来封？
Why use cement?
是不准闲杂人等出入！
... it's to keep out intruders!
那些警察叫律师应付，是！
Ask our barristers to deaI
with the poIice, yes!
干嘛？
What is it?
你怎么找个古人回来呢？
Why you invite an ancient person
home?
他怎么说也救过我一命
He did save my Iife
什么人来的？神经病吗？
Who is he? He's nuts?
关公呀
Master Kwan
这个世界哪有关公？
There's no Master Kwan in the worId
你和我日拜夜拜，怎会没有？
sure there is, we worship him
day and night
你自己信不信？
Do you beIieve in him?
那你证明他不是给我看吧！
OK, prove to me that he is not!
一会有人来，他佛一般坐在那怎么办？
What if he just sits there Iike a dummy
when the others arrive?
你还不快上去找件时装给他换？
Go and get him some modern cIothes
at once
那就不碍眼了，去吧
He'II Iook more naturaI. Go
妖孽！
EviI!
干嘛不看？不好看吗？
Why don't you watch? Not good?
非礼勿视呀，嫂子
sister, it's immoraI
关二哥，久哥请你上房换套衣服
Master Kwan, Jim wants you to change
your cIothes
好！请…
OK, pIease ...
四大公司中，亏佬基已不在了
Kei is no more the head of
the 4 organizations
如果不是彭焦，一定是陆老四！
so if it's not Pang Chiu
it must be Luk see!
是彭焦！
It's Pang Chiu!
一定是陆老四！
It must be Luk see!
彭焦…    陆老四…
Pang Chiu ... Luk see ...
我进来，不打扰大家吧？
Do I disturb you if I come in?
不打扰，我们只是闭话家常
No, we're mereIy chatting
未请教？
You are?
我乃是关云长！
I'm Kwan Wan Cheung!
就是这位大哥救了我
This master has saved my Iife
你真是关公？
You're reaIIy Master Kwan?
正是
Yes
那你就是神了
so you're a god
神什么问题都懂回答
Being a god, you must know everything
那我问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question
请讲
Go ahead
为什么那么多人你不救
There're so many peopIe who need heIp
要救我们久哥呢？
but why wouId you rescue Brother Jim?
太多人要我帮忙
There're many peopIe
who need my heIp ...
我不可能每个都保佑
... I can't heIp everyone
惟有隔段时间随便找个人来帮
I can onIy heIp peopIe randomIy
做人做神都是一样
Being a god is Iike being human
你隔段时间做些事情
If you do some miracIes
from time to time ...
人们就会觉得你很灵
... peopIe wiII beIieve in you
我没话问了
I have no more questions
不过我们正在开会
But we're having a meeting
随便，我不出声，我在这里听
Go ahead, I won't make any noise
I'II onIy Iisten
那么我们继续聊天吧
Let's chat
你有没有怀疑过他是卧底？
Maybe he's a spy?
这样卧法，你会不会？
WouId you spy Iike that?
二哥，带你出去吃东西吧
Master Kwan, Iet's go get something
to eat
我一片赤胆帮各位
I do my best to heIp you
大家应该将心比明月
so you must be honest
事无不可对人言
and don't hide anything from others
好！
Good!
好一句将心比明月！
We must aII be honest!
我们一起鼓掌欢迎关二哥加入！
Let's appIaud and weIcome
Master Kwan!
大哥，警察来了
Boss, the poIice is here
一波未平，一波又起
TroubIes keep coming
怎样，叶警官？
What is it, Officer Yip?
何君愉受了重伤
Ho Kwun Yue is seriousIy injured
附近有两个怀疑是非法入境者死了
and two iIIegaI immigrants died nearby
周围有很多枪战痕迹
There was shooting invoIved
你在不在现场？
Were you there?
不在，我也是刚刚才知道这件事
No, I've just Iearnt of that
那砘锸羌榈
That guy is eviI
据我调查
After investigating ...
那地方任先生经常去的
... we found that it is a pIace you visit
frequentIy, Mr. Yam
我不明白
I don't understand
我不明白什么叫经常去的地方
I don't understand what you mean
by frequent
我想问你认识个叫JoJo张的女孩吗？
Do you know a girI caIIed
Jo Jo Cheung?
可能认识，可能不认识
Maybe yes and maybe no
不过我对这个名字真的没什么印象
but I have no impression to this name
有件事…
There's one thing ...
但任太太在此，我不知该不该问？
I wonder if I shouId ask
since Mrs. Yam is here
我刚刚将心比明月，你问吧
I just took an oath to be honest
go ahead
JoJo张跟你有什么关系？
What is your reIationship
with Jo Jo Cheung?
确实…是没什么关系
There is ... no speciaI reIationship
叶警官，我想这些问题
Officer Yip, I prefer ...
等我律师来了才答你
... to answer this with my Iawyer present
你这次上来，无非是怀疑…
You come here because you suspect ...
我们久哥是个受害者
... Brother Jim is a victim
好，我不问
Okay, I won't ask
但可以说话吧
... but I wiII teII instead
据我们情报科的资料显示
According to the information we coIIect
JoJo张是任先生的情妇
Jo Jo Cheung is Mr. Yam's mistress
命案就发生在她家附近
And the murders occurred near
her home
不知道任先生当时在不在现场
I want to know if Mr. Yam was
on the scene at that time
希望他可以协助我们调查
I hope he wiII heIp with
our investigation
就这么多
That's aII
我不管是不是陆老四干的
I don't care if Luk see did it or not
我们就利用这机会开战
We must use this chance
to decIare war on him
我们刚刚需要一个借口
We just need an excuse
所以就算不是他，也算他倒霉吧
so if he wasn't the pIotter
then he just has bad Iuck
本来阿愉受了伤
I was worried about my safety
我有点担心自己的安全
now
Yue is injured
但现在有关二哥显灵帮我
But since Master Kwan is here
to heIp me
正是天助我也
I know the heavens is on my side
对吧，关二哥？
Right, Master Kwan?
我有个提议
I have a suggestion
二哥有话说，大家鼓掌
Let's appIaud, Master Kwan
has something to say
我认为
I think that ...
大家应该化干戈为玉帛
... you shouId stop aII rivaIries
不是吧？
Come on
我好不容易才找到借口开战
It's not easy finding an excuse
to decIare war
我认为无论对敌对友
Whether it is to friend or to foe ...
都应该讲个义字
... LoyaIty is important
我认为…
I think that ...
What IoyaIty?
义什么？
No wonder you're ranked second
among the 3 sworn brothers
难怪你一辈子做人家的老二
我知道你为何失败，就是太老实！
It's because you're naive and stupid!
做大哥不是这样想事情的，关老二
A boss can't think Iike that
Master Kwan
久哥…
Brother Jim ...
我以事论事而已
I'm just pointing things out
他是没当过大哥嘛
He's never been a boss
嫂子，你很不开心吗？
sister, you're upset?
我跟我老公这么多年
I've been with my husband
for many years
混女人他一定有
I know he fooIs around
我也不想去问
... and I never ask him about them
在外头逢场作兴在所难免
In this Iine of work, men fooI around
我以为他出来玩，出钱出力不出感情
I thought he onIy pIays but doesn't
get invoIved
这叫尊重嘛
That is mutuaI respect
想不到他在外面有个女人
But I didn't think he wouId
keep a mistress
真傻
I'm so fooIish
这叫恋爱
so this is Iove
你不明白这些的
You won't understand
不过很小意思
but it's triviaI
我明白
I understand
当年千里送嫂
In my days, I saw sister-in-Iaw off
你猜我为何要月下看春秋？
Why do you think I read under
the moonIight?
我也是一个男子
I'm aIso a man
你不是在开会吗？
Aren't you having a meeting?
我真的越听越心寒
The more I Iisten, the more scared I am
嫂子
sister
敢问如今世上，还有谁说忠义二字？
Is there anyone who stiII speaks of
IoyaIty in the worId?
忠义，说出来就难听了
LoyaIty sounds stupid for modern
peopIe
实在落后极了
It's out dated
拜归拜，虽然天天拜
Though we worship you everyday ...
但信是两码事，关二哥
... whether we beIieve in you is
another matter, Master Kwan
我这次显灵，真有点失望
Coming here has a disappointment
for me
嫂子，你告诉你老公
sister, teII your husband ...
叫他好自为之
... to tread carefuIIy
不然，拜谁都没用
... or eIse no god can heIp him
关二哥！
Master Kwan!
关公！
苏花
sophie
关二哥！
Master Kwan!
苏花，那个关老二呢？
sophie, where's Master Kwan?
走了
He's gone
不是吧？不说一声就走了？
Has he? He Ieft without a word?
我想他真是关二哥
I think he's reaIIy Master Kwan
为什么要加入黑社会？
Why must we join the triad?
威风有钱有女人，什么都有
Power, money, women
we'II get them aII if we join it
砍人的事我也不怕
And I'm not scared to chop peopIe up
天天那么多人死，也不见我死
I survive even though many die
everyday
看我的样子…
Look at me ...
一看就知道是长命的那种
You can teII I'II Iive Iong
我弟弟…为你们开片死了
My brother ... died in a fight for you
你不是说过会好好照顾他吗？
Didn't you say you'd take good
care of him?
人都死了，还哭什么？
He's dead, why cry anymore?
等会我们去买个Prada
Let me buy you a Prada
我不是需要一个Prada
I don't want a Prada
哪有女人不要Prada呢？
Which woman doesn't want a Prada?
我买两个给你！
I'II buy you two!
小姐，为什么没有白色花？
Miss, why aren't there white fIowers?
白色花刚刚卖完了
The white fIowers are aII soId out
其它颜色好不好？
What about other coIours?
我要配搭颜色，用来变魔术的
I need them for a magic show
不好意思，帮不了你
sorry, I can't heIp you
我想我死了，也不应该向你表白
I don't think I shouId've reveaIed
my Iove for you
就是嘛
Right
搞到现在…
And now ...
多尴尬
It's embarrassing
我本来不是同性恋，我一向喜欢女人
I didn't used to be gay
I aIways Ioved women
直到跟了你
... untiI I worked for you
跟你，是因为我服你
I work for you because I admire you
我很敬佩你
I respect you
我开始关心你
I started to care for you
慢慢…
Then sIowIy ...
我觉得，我真的可以为你死
I found that I couId reaIIy die for you
后来我也很害怕
I was afraid at that time
我觉得这世上，没有谁比你更重要
... when I found that no one was
more important than you
包括我自己
... not even me
我知道我失败了
I know I've faiIed
我…
I ...
大概都理解的
Maybe I can understand
只是大概…不是全部
some ... not aII
现在我伤成这样
Now that I'm seriousIy injured ...
不知还有没有机会为你卖命
I don't know if I can work
for you anymore
想起以前，阿卓和我都是你的左右手
I remember Jeff and I being your heIp
阿卓现在还在狱中
But Jeff is stiII in jaiI now
我真的很担心你
I reaIIy worried about you
说起来…
Like you said ...
我也很久没去探望阿卓了
I haven't visited Jeff for a Iong time
久哥
Brother Jim
我还有没有机会跟你？
Do I stiII have a chance working
for you?
等你伤好了再说吧
Wait tiII you have recovered
不过…
But ...
我就死也不再和你去桑拿
I'II never go to the sauna with you again
久哥
Brother Jim
我真的没猜错，你真的再来看我
I knew you wouId come to see me again
那班砘锷窬病，说你把我忘了
Those bastards keep saying you have
forgotten me
他们都不明白，什么叫好兄弟！
They don't understand what buddies are
对不起
sorry
这几年你多忙，哪有空呀
You've been busy aII these years
you reaIIy had no time
众多兄弟跟你混
... you're responsibIe for a Iot of men
大哥，大嫂怎样？
Boss, how is sister?
有没有替你生一两个？
You have babies now?
你现在有空，搞一下她吧
You have some free time
make Iove to her
不用来探我嘛
You needn't visit me
牢我还有得坐，你怕没机会见吗？
I stiII have to stay here for a Iong time
you can aIways come Iater on
不过我真是…
But it's reaIIy ...
没想到你会来看我，不是…
... it's reaIIy a surprise to see you, no ...
我意思是，没想到你今天会来看我
I mean I never expected you'd
come today
有些突然
It's so sudden
卓，真的很对不起
Jeff, I'm reaIIy sorry
大哥
Boss
我的家靠你了
My famiIy reIies on you
我的子女，现在读中学了
My chiIdren go to secondary schooI now
我要好好感谢你呢
so I must show my gratitude to you
探监名单上，第一个名字就是你
You're on the top of my visitors' Iist
这么久都没改过
and this has never changed
老婆儿子女儿，这星期来就调别的名
For my famiIy, they must take turn
to come here
因为我知道…
I knew ...
你一定会像今天这样来看我
you'II come to visit me, just Iike today
卓，你入狱这么久
Jeff, you've been here for a Iong time
你有没有想过，我是个坏大哥？
Have you ever thought I was
a bad boss?
我欺骗你
I took advantage of you
就这样摆你进来
I Iet you be sent to jaiI
不理你死活，不理你老婆子女
I didn't care about you, or your famiIy
我自己就在外面风流快活
And I Iive the high Iife outside
有没有？
Have you?
大哥
Boss
很多人以为我傻
Guys thought I was stupid
我一点也不傻
but I'm not stupid at aII
跟什么大哥，我自己知道
I know which boss I work for
我告诉你
I teII you
我从没后悔跟你
I have never regretted working for you
没后悔
Never
做兄弟，有今生无来世！
Life is short, it's Iuck we become
buddies!
我常跟人家说，我最自豪…
I aIways teII others I'm proud ...
就是有你这个大哥
... of my boss
出来混，那么容易找个好大哥吗？
It's hard to find a good boss
in the underworId, right?
听说…阿愉有事
I've heard that ... something happened
to Yue
他现在怎样？
How is he now?
现在谁在你身边？
Who's protecting you now?
没事的
It'II be aIright
我现在有很多人护着我
Many peopIe are protecting me
不行的
How can this be?
现在的新人很贪生
PeopIe nowadays are cowards
不同我和阿愉
They're not Iike Yue and me
他们不会奋不顾身的
They wouIdn't risk themseIves for you
有没有危险，大哥？
Are you in danger, boss?
告诉我吧
TeII me
我出不去，也可以帮你想想呀
Even though I'm in jaiI
I can figure it out for you
你别想太多
Don't think so much
好好的坐完这几年
There're onIy a few more years for you
告诉我，好吗？
TeII me, pIease
我没事，你放心
I'm fine, don't worry
我现在知道怎样做一个好大哥
I know how to be a good boss now
放开手
Take your hands off
久哥，我已经查过
Brother Jim, I've done some
investigating
老表华志在自保，不足为患
Wah isn't our rivaI, aII he wants is
seIf-defence
至于彭焦…我跟他说
And for Pang Chiu ... I've taIked to him
西边赌场和人蛇两项都算他一份
I agree to Iet him share with us the
interest of casino and iIIegaI immigrants
只要他不插手
... as Iong as he stays out
他老人家说现在风头火势
He says the poIice is watching cIoseIy
应该是不会露面了
... so he won't show up
这两个星期，还去黄山旅行
He says he's going to traveI
in the MainIand
说回来再约你喝茶
... and wiII have tea with you
when he returns
酒楼那边布置成怎样？
How's the arrangement
at the restaurant?
据我估计，我们两边各有四百多人
I estimate we both have 4OO peopIe
each
如果有需要，可以再召集五百多
If there's such a need
I can get extra 5OO
不过当中总有一两百是同一班人
... though some of them beIong to
其实大家心知肚明，根本打不起来
As we aII know, there won't be
a reaI fight
有时我真不明白
I just wonder
那砘镂什么喜欢花这个钱
why that guy must spend this money
久哥，四哥在二楼等你
Brother Jim, Brother see is waiting
for you
任老久，这么迟？
Jim Yam, why so Iate?
这么早来，急着投胎吗？
What's the hurry?
老久，今天趁大家人齐
Jim, as aII our men are here
你想怎样谈？
TeII me what you want
想怎样谈都可以
Let's taIk frankIy
我就想跟你关起门慢慢谈
I want to taIk to you aIone
谈得来的，就完完整整走出去
If we reach agreement
we can both Ieave safeIy
这样也行呀
It's fine with me
亏佬基的生意，大家都有兴趣
We're both interested in Kei's business
他的旗有没有人能出来撑
We aII know he has no one
大家都心照
taking charge of his business
任老久，你觉得…
Jim Yam, what do you think ...
应该怎样分才为之公道？
... is a fair way to divide it?
什么事这么好笑？
What's so funny?
任老久！你听不到我说什么吗？
Jim Yam, didn't you hear what I said?
你这么大声说话，不怕外面打起来吗？
Aren't you scared a fight wiII start
outside if you speak so Ioud?
那你为什么大声笑？
Then why are you Iaughing IoudIy?
推测笑不会令外面打起来吧
I think my Iaughter wiII keep a fight
from starting
但是你这么大声说话
But you speak so IoudIy
外面会以为我们谈不成的
... they wiII think we can't reach
说实话，你到底想怎样？
TeII me, what exactIy do you want?
那我不跟你谈了！
I won't taIk with you then!
别掀桌子吧
Don't turn the tabIe
当心
Watch out
你可不可正正经经地谈？
Can you be serious and taIk to me?
譬如不要笑呀
Can you refrain from Iaughing?
好，不笑
OK, I won't Iaugh
我问你，我们怎样分亏佬基的生意？
I ask you, how can we divide
Kei's business?
你又是这样！
You're Iaughing again!
对不起，不好意思
sorry, excuse me
我真的…真的忍不住…
I reaIIy ... can't heIp ...
有什么好笑？我问你呀！
What is it so funny? TeII me!
还分什么？你要我就全让给你
Why divide? If you want
you can take it aII
任老久，你玩什么花样？
Jim Yam, what do you mean by that?
你啃得下的，就全啃掉吧
Take it if you can swaIIow it aII
但问题是，我认为你啃不下
But the probIem is: you cannot swaIIow
it aII by yourseIf
还有，如果我现在什么都不要
And if I abandon it aII
就这样走出去
and Iet you take over Kei's business
任你独吞亏佬基的生意
whiIe waIking out with bare hands
人家会怎样说你？
What wiII others say about you?
你肯定理亏，你欺负孤儿寡妇
They'II say you buIIy Kei's famiIy
我就变成忠的
I'II be regarded as honorabIe
到时还要替阿基的老婆出头
Bosses of aII areas wiII stand up
for Kei's wife
谁不站在我这边？
They'II sureIy stand on my side
那生意迟早还不是我的？
Kei's business wiII return to me by then
但你就与天下为敌了
And you? You'II become
the common enemy
所以我一想起就觉得好笑
I just can't heIp Iaughing
when I think of this
笑得合不上嘴巴…
I just can't heIp Iaughing out Ioud ...
其实我今天来，根本没打算跟你争
I come today not to have a fight
你要就全拿走吧
Take it aII if you want
陆老四，你干什么？
Luk see, what are you doing?
你别耍花样
Don't pIay any tricks
我…我有…
I ... I have ...
你想玩我？
You pIaying with me?
我有心脏病…
I have heart disease ...
不是吧？
Do you?
有心脏病就别出来谈判嘛
You shouIdn't have come
if you were sick
你歇一歇，我去叫人
Take a rest, I'II get heIp
不行，如果我现在出去叫人
No, if I go out and caII for heIp
人家以为我杀你，那怎么行？
They'II think I kiIIed you
what shaII I do?
坏了，好的不灵丑的灵
It's bad, the bad aIways happens
有没有药？
You have medications with you?
陆老四！你现在不能死呀！
Luk see, you can't die now!
你死了，江湖就腥风血雨了！
The underworId wiII go nuts
if you die now!
万一我有事…
If anything happens to me ...
我拜你…
I beg you ...
我…我有个私生子
I ... I have a iIIegitimate son
你要帮我证明
You must be his witness
我要分三分一家产给他呀
... I want to give him one-third
of my properties
你帮我证…
Be his witness ...
陆老四！
Luk see!
报案中心，这里出事啦！
999, something happened here!
大哥…
Boss ...
任先生，场面好热闹呀
Mr. Yam, it's very exciting here
干嘛要花这么多钱呢？
Why must you spend so much?
对了，我们刚刚为这件事开了个档案
Right, we've just opened a fiIe
for this incident
叫江湖告急
It's caIIed Jiang Hu Gao Ji
但是我想来想去
But though I try hard ...
都想不到江湖的英文是什么
I don't know what the EngIish name
for Jiang Hu is
你在江湖日子甚久…
You've been in the Jiang Hu for ages ...
你知不知道？
Do you know?
任老久
Jim Yam
江湖是你的，我认输了
The underworId beIongs to you
I've Iost
我输给了自己
I've Iost to myseIf
还有…
Furthermore ...
私生子那件事，你要发誓不说出去
... you must swear you won't teII a souI
about my iIIegitimate son
我女人不知道的
My wife doesn't know about him
好，我答应你，我发誓
OK, I promise, I swear
说实话，有没有找人杀我？
TeII me frankIy, have you ever
sent men to kiII me?
我肯定没有
Of course not
不过我们闯荡江湖这么久
But we've been in the underworId
for a Iong time
干了那么多事
and we've done so many things
又何必斤斤计较谁干的呢？
Why must you insist on finding out
who did that?
今天是他，明天可能又是别人
It may be him today, or may be
another guy tomorrow
每天的答案都不同
The answer is different everyday
没意思的
It's meaningIess
阿虎
Tiger
自从阿基不在之后
since Kei died ...
我一个女人什么都不懂
I found that I knew nothing
about his business
儿子又不肯接手
And my son doesn't want to take over
你知道，那班小混混日夜争吵
You know, the scoundreIs shout
and nag aII day Iong
你不服我，我不服你
And they can't get aIong peacefuIIy
我真不知道该怎样才好
I reaIIy don't know what to do
大嫂，你为什么要找我来谈？
sister, why do you want to taIk to me?
现在我在这家医院做义工
I work as a voIunteer in this hospitaI
now
为末期癌症病人做善终服务
I heIp the cancer patients
at their finaI stage
生意迟早要交给别人
I must hand over the business
to others sooner or Iater
但我想交给一个能干的人
Of course I want someone capabIe
大嫂，你现在最不放心是什么？
sister, what worries you the most?
听说洪宝的任因久在打我们的主意
PeopIe say Jim Yam of Hung Bo
wants to get invoIved
所以我很担心
I'm very worried
不过看起来
WeII ...
那个任因久的品格也不错
... that Jim Yam seems not a bad guy
阿基的丧事，他落力尽心
He did a Iot in Kei's funeraI
他还花了不少钱
He spent a Iot of money as weII
我…我真的不懂打算
I ... I reaIIy don't know what to do
万一他真的要过来搞我们，那…
If ever he comes to stir up troubIe, then
我一个女人，一把年纪
I'm a woman, an oId woman
难道真要拿刀跟他拼吗？
shouId I take a knife and fight him?
大嫂，你放心吧
sister, don't worry
我知道该怎样做
I know what to do
阿虎，你真要帮我才好
Tiger, you must heIp me
放心吧，大嫂
Don't worry, sister
大嫂今晚心情不好，我们做事小心点
sister is in bad mood tonight
Iet's be on our toes
久哥说今晚不想太多人在这里
Boss said he didn't want
too many peopIe here
你们三个在街口等
You three wait on the corner
这里就交给你了
You take charge here
我任因久行走江湖这么多年
I've been in the underworId
for a Iong time
不知经历过多少次大大小小的谈判
and have gone through numerous
negotiations ...
但今晚这一次，我觉得最难
The negotation this evening is
the most difficuIt
因为对手是苏花
because my opponent is sophie
你班兄弟呢？
Where are your men?
我没叫他们进来
I didn't ask them to come in
自从跟你回来香港
since coming back to HK with you
每次吃饭都是几桌几桌的
... your men are around us
whenever we eat
这样的环境很少见
such a quiet meaI is rare
JoJo一
那天见习督察说的那个女孩
The girI mentioned by that trainee ...
她跟我三年了
... has been with me for 3 years
我打算给她一笔钱，以后不再见她
I'm giving her some money
and I'm breaking it off
你有话就完完整整说出来谈妥它
You can discuss with me if
you have anything in mind
用不着这样嘛！
Don't be Iike this!
你知道多年来我最介意是什么？
You know what I mind most
你就是介意我外面有女人
You mind me having a mistress
害得你好没面子
... so that you Iose face
的确是很介意，但不是最介意
I reaIIy mind it, but not the most
那你最介意什么？
What do you mind the most then?
我最介意你当众挖苦我
I mind most when you keep teIIing
others ...
说我不能生育
... that I haven't had a baby
我真的介意到不得了
I reaIIy mind that
多年来，我很想替你生个儿子
I want to have your chiId
不能生育不是我一个人的责任
... but I'm not the onIy one responsibIe
for it
难道要我叫你以后别做缺德的事？
I can't ask you never to act badIy, right?
我梦见我生了个孩子
I dreamt of having a baby
没屁眼的
But he has no anus
恐怖极了
Isn't it horribIe?
那孩子没屁眼的
Our baby has no anus
你怎也想像不出多恶心呀
You can imagine how awfuI it is
你怎么不早点跟我说？
Why didn't you teII me?
有用吗？
WouId it heIp?
你还不是那句
You wouId mereIy say ...
我们出来混，早就预着了
we expect this kind of stuff Iiving
in the underworId
我们回英国
Let's go back to EngIand
你和我回一次英国吧
Go back to EngIand with me, just once
你下次找女人，可别让我知道
And don't Iet me know
if you have another mistress
在这等我
Wait for me here
小心点
Be carefuI
你怎样？
How are you?
别理我…
Never mind me ...
他来了…
Here he comes ...
你去吧
Go now
任因久
Jim Yam
我说过会还钱给你
I've said I'II pay you back the money
八婆…
Bitch ...
这么多钻石…
so many diamonds ...
是什么表？
What brand is it?
江施丹顿呀
Constantin
住手！
stop it!
趴下！别乱来！
Face the ground! Take it easy!
你怎样？
How are you?
你要杀他先杀了我！
KiII me first, if you must kiII him!
你很爱他吗？
You Iove him so much?
你说什么肉麻话？
What are you babbIing about?
放了他
Let him go
小姐，你在找什么？
Miss, what are you Iooking for?
我在找车匙
My car key
明明放在袋里
I put it in the pocket
不是左边就是右边了
It must be either in Ieft or right pocket
不在左，也不在右
Neither in the Ieft nor right
在里面
It's inside
谢谢你
Thanks
不用客气
You're weIcome
警察先生
sir
是
Yes
你去哪里？
Where are you going?
回警署
Back to the poIice station
远不远？
Far away?
走十分钟左右
About 1O minutes on foot
我送你吧？
Let me give you a Iift
好的
sure
我见过这个女孩
I've seen this girI before
几年前，她在一间服装贵得我买不起
A few years ago, she was a saIesIady ...
的西装店里当售货员
... in a brand name boutique
忘了告诉你
I forget to teII you
回来之前我买下这里
I bought back this pIace
before we came back here
打算回去住它两三个月
I'm going to Iive here
for a coupIe of months
要不要叫风水师传
shaII we ask the Feng shiu Master
和室内设计师来收拾一下？
and Interior Designer to furnish
the pIace?
我们回不了头了，别勉强吧
We can't turn back now
so don't force it
怎样？就拿三几百万出来装修吧
What? Then cough up $3 miIIion
to renovate it
那就先弄好窗子
Have that window mended first
别老是雨天漏水
I hate rain dripping in